Guide to the Evarts Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Jeremiah Evarts, 1798-1833; Series I; 28.75 linear feet (51 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Chamberlain, Daniel, (missionary), 1823 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Charlestown: Harris Library, S. G. Payson, 1822 December 24 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Cheever, George B., 1830 March 13, August 23 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Christian, P. W. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      See: box 3, folder 99
    - Clay, Henry, 1830 August 23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Cleveland, John (incomplete draft), 1821 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Coe, George W., 1822 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, Stephen Twining, 1823 January 4 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Coodey, William S. (Cherokee Nation), 1830 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Cornelius, Elias (includes letters of introduction for Duncan Hennen and Gerard H. Hallock), 1822-1824 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Cornelius, M. N., 1823 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Crocker and Brewster, Boston publishers, 1823, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Crocker, U., 1826 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Daggett, Henry, 1822 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Davis, Asahel, 1823 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Day, Jeremiah, 1811 June 6, 1830 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Dee, Washington, 1825 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Denny, George, 1830 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Dixon, D. R. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Letter of introduction for Sertius D. Southworth, 1825 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Dutton, M. R., 1824 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Dwight, Sereno Edwards and Susan E. D., 1823-1825 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1815 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Echevere, Sarah, 1831 March 23 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Edwards, Justin, 1825 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Ely, E. S. (draft), 1830 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Evarts, James (father) (original ALS of Jeremiah Evarts to James Evarts, 1818 Jan, is filed in Folio 49B), 1818 Jan, 1819 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 1/1
    - Evarts, John Jay (son), 1830 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 3
    - Letters from Yale College (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Evarts, Jonathan Todd (brother), 1807-1808, 1826-1829 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 8
    - Evarts, Mary (daughter), 1823, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/3
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1810-1817 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/6
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1818 January-July (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/7
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1822 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1824-1825 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1826-1827 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 3/5
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1828 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1829 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 4/4
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1830 April 17, August 16 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/2
    - Evarts, Mehetabel (Sherman) Barnes (wife), 1831 February-May, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 4/6
    - Evarts, Sarah (Todd) (mother), 1800-1806 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 4/1
    - Evarts, Sarah (Todd) and Todd, Matilda, 1798 October 22 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Everett, Edward, 1830-1831 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 5
    - Farrar, Samuel, 1818 January 9, 1823 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Fay, Warren, 1822 March 13, 1825 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Fendall, P. W., 1830 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Ferry, William M. Excerpts from a letter to Jeremiah Evarts, 1827 Jan 24 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      See: box 2, folder 57
    - Field, David Dudley, 1826 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Foster, Eleazer, 1803 March 27, October 24 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Frelinghuysen, Theodore, 1830-1831 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Gates, James W., 1826 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Gibbs, William, 1826 May 30, August 14 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Goodrich, Horatio and David, 1827 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Graves, Mary Evarts, 1823 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Gray, Henry, 1822 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Green, J., 1823 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Greene, David, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Griffin, Edward Dorr, 1810, 1824, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 2/1
    - Grimke, Thomas S., 1830 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Hale, David, Jr., 1822 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Hall, Gordon (missionary, Bombay, India, re: missionaries returning to the United States), 1826 Feb, March 2 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Hallock, William A. (includes ALS for Rufus Anderson), 1824 October 12, 26 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Hamilton, John and Matilda, 1824 August 21 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Harper, Harriet, 1831 March 26, April 9 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Harrington, Joseph, 1823 August (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Hill, Henry, 1823-1830 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 5/1
    - Hill, Joshua W. (missionary about to embark from New Bedford for Hawaii), 1830 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Hoadley, George (copy), 1807 February 5 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Holley, Horace, 1807 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Holmes, Abiel, 1826 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Holt, Charles, 1830 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Homes, Henry, 1823 October 21 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Homes, Mrs. J., 1825 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Hough, John, 1822-1826 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Hubbard, M(ary Ann), 1825 December 27 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Hubbard, Samuel, 1825-1830 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Hubbard, Thomas, 1826 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Hubbard, William J. (Box 2, Folder 69)
      See: box 3, folder 132
    - Huntington, A. J., 1822 March 28, 30 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Ibbetson, N. N. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Letter of introduction for G. W. Blagden, 1826 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Janes, Horace (includes letter of introduction for James W. Gates), 1826 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Jay, John, 1813 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Jenks, William, 1823-1826 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 6
    - Jewett, Salla, 1825 February 25, 1826 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Johnson, Sherman, 1823 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Kerr, Dorcas M., 1823 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Kimball, James L., 1831 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Kingsley, James Luce, 1830 July 5, 14 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Kirk, Edward Norris, 1829 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Lakeman, Elizabeth, 1823 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Lane, Ebenezer, 1824 June 5 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Laurence, J. B., 1822 December 2 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Le Baron, Samuel (ALS to William Reed), 1830 December 17 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Leech, William (re: subscribers to the Missionary Herald ), 1825 January (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Leland, A. W., 1824 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Lord, Eleazar, 1822-1827 (Box 3, Folder 82)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/5
    - Lord, Eleazar, 1829-1830 January 12 (Box 3, Folder 83)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 5/7
    - Lord, Eleazar, 1830 January 23-1830 Dec, n.y. October 27 (Box 3, Folder 84)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 6/3
    - McDowell, John (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Letter of introduction for Gustavus Princker, 1824 October 14 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - McDowell, William A., 1825 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - McIntire, Charles (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Letter of introduction for Martha Spalding, 1823 May 21 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Mason, Lowell, 1822 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Maxwell, William, 1823 October 16, 1830 April 22 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Maxwell, William: extracts of Jeremiah Evarts' letter, sent to E. C. Gracy by William Maxwell, 1835 April 3 (Box 3, Folder 87A)
    - Mead, Asa, 1830 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Meigs, B. C. (missionary in Ceylon), 1827 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Metcalf, E., 1831 March 26 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Morse, Jedidiah, 1823-1824 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Morse, Sidney E. re: Connecticut Journal and proposed American Observer, 1823 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Nevius, John S., 1827 March 8 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Newton, Frederic, 1825 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - North American Review (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - Jared Sparks, editor, 1827 July 31 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Alexander Hill Everett, editor, 1830 April 5 (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - F. T. Gray, 1830 August-November (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Nott, Samuel, 1823 February 8 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Odiorne, George, 1822, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Odiorne, S., 1824 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Olcott, Thomas W., 1825 November 26, December 3 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Palmer, Benjamin M., 1823, 1825 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Parker, B. C. C., 1824 December 30, 1825 December 30 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Parker, Ebenezer, 1824 October 13, November 12 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Perit, Pelatiah, 1831 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Phillips, James, 1825 March 2 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Poor, Daniel, 1827 August 3, December 20 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Porter, Ebenezer, 1823 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - also ALS of Benjamin M. Palmer to Ebenezer Porter, with a note from Porter (to Jeremiah Evarts?), n.y. March (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Prescott, Benjamin (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Letter of introduction for S. G. Downs, 1825 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Proctor, John Cleaveland, 1824-1826 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Randolph, John, 1812 December 30 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Robinson, M., 1821 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Rogers, G., 1825 December 27 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Ross, John (head of Coosa Cherokee Nation), 1830 April 6, July 24 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Russell, William, 1826 January 3 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Sabine, James, 1822 August 30, 1823 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Scudder, C., 1827 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Shaw, S., Jr., 1829 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Shedd, William, 1825 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Sherman, David Austin, 1826-1830 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Sherman, Roger, 1823-1830 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Smith, Ethan, 1823 October 21 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Southard, Samuel Lewis, Secretary of the Navy (incomplete draft re: a consul for the Sandwich Islands), 1828 November (Box 3, Folder 111)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/l
    - Spencer, Ambrose, 1830 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Spring, Gardiner, 1825 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Storey, C. W., 1831 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Stuart, Moses, 1823, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Storrs, R. S. (Box 3, Folder 112)
      See: box 3, folder 16
    - Swann, Roswell Randall, 1802 October 2, 1803 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Tappan, John (Box 3, Folder 113)
      See: box 3, folder 134
    - Taylor, Oliver S. re: The Panoplist, 1823 September 29, October 20 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Thayer, Jechonias, 1823 October 23 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Thomas, Isaiah, 1825 November 5 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Todd, John, 1820-1825 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Tracy, Martha Sherman (Evarts) (daughter), 1831 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Treadwell, John, 1821 July 21 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Turner, Harriet B., 1826 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Tyler, Joseph, 1822-1826 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Wadsworth, Daniel, 1823 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Walley, S. H., 1822 February 27, 1823 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Waln, Robert Jr. (Box 3, Folder 121)
      See: box 3, folder 141
    - Washburn, Hercules (brother-in-law), 1818-1821 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Washburn, Sarah (Evarts) (sister), 1803-1814 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Washburn, Sarah (Evarts) (sister), 1816-1829 (Box 3, Folder 124)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 3/2
    - Webster, E. W., 1831 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Webster, Noah, 1810 October 24 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Wells, Noah B. and H., 1825 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - White, John, 1801-1805 (Box 3, Folder 126)
      Letters to JE/From JE: 0/4
    - White, William B., 1824 December 2 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Whiting, Nathan, 1825 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Whitney, Henrietta F. (re: The Recorder ), 1823 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Whitney, Paul, 1822 July 19 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Whittelsey, Samuel, 1824 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Wilby, F., 1825 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Wilcox, Mary and Wealthy, 1823 March 29 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Wilder, Samson Vryling Stoddard (includes letter of introduction from Jeremiah Evarts for Jonas King), 1821 August 15, 1825 August 30 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Williams, Hannah, 1825 January 26 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Williston, Payson, 1824 July 7 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Winthrop, Augusta T., 1820 May 18 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Wisner, Benjamin B., 1823-1826 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Wisner, S. H., n.y. November 29 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Wood, Joseph, 1825 October 27 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Woods, Leonard, 1823, 1824, 1830 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Worcester, Leonard, 1826 August 21 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Worcester, Samuel, 1811 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Worcester, S. M., 1830 February 28, March 8 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Letters of introduction and recommendation written for Jeremiah Evarts by Timothy Dwight, Leonard Worcester and Jedidiah Morse, 1802-1809 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Invitations, 1822-1830, undated (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Notices of meetings, 1822-1830 (Box 3, Folder 139-140)
    - Correspondence related to biography of Roger Sherman by Robert Waln, Jr., 1822-1823 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Sympathy letters on the death of Jeremiah Evarts (Box 3, Folder 141)
      See: box 44, folder 13
    - ALS to Ebenezer C. Tracy from David Dudley Field (re: Jeremiah Evarts' conversion to Christianity) enclosing a copy of an article written in 1802 on the religious revival at Yale College, n.y. March 31 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Subject File (Box 4)
  - The Panoplist
    - Contracts and agreements re: editing and publishing, Jeremiah Evarts, editor, 1810-1815 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Letters to the editor, 1814 April-November (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Index for Volume XIII for the year 1817 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - "Proposals by Samuel T. Armstrong…for continuing by subscription a periodical work, entitled the Panoplist and Missionary Herald ", 1818 January 1 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Financial estimate by Jeremiah Evarts, undated (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Correspondence re: contents, publication, and expenses (Box 4, Folder 147)
      See: box 1, folder 1
  - American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
    - Certificate of membership of Jeremiah Evarts, 1812 September 17 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Prudential Committee minutes and newsletters, 1815-1826, undated (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Notes and memoranda by Jeremiah Evarts and others, 1816, 1823-1830, undated (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Notes and memoranda written or received by Jeremiah Evarts in the course of travel commissioned by the Board, 1817, 1822-1831, undated (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Statements of balances from the treasurer, Jeremiah Evarts, 1817-1821 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - "Address of the female missionaries to Ceylon to their sisters in America," with a letter of explanation from Miron Winslow, a missionary in the same party, 1819 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Order for a printing press to be furnished to Jeremiah Evarts at cost, from H. O. Stansbury to Elihu White, 1821 May 16 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Eleventh report, list of persons who received copies, 1821 February-May (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Letters from missions. C. Byington, Elliot (Miss?); George Ogilvy and G. Hall, India; J. C. Brigham, Buenos Aires; David Malo, Oahu, Hawaii, 1821-1827 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Commission appointing Jeremiah Evarts as a special agent of the Board, signed by Leonard Woods, 1822 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Report on the Foreign Mission School at Cornwall, 1825 October 26 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - and an invitation to a joint meeting of the A. B. C. F. M. and the United Foreign Missionary Society, 1826 November 27 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Reports (fragments) from missionaries, 1826, 1828, undated (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Incomplete copy of a letter from P. Bayssière to his children explaining the reasons for his conversion to the Protestant faith (intended for publication in the Missionary Herald ?), 1826 December 31 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Reports from the Sandwich Island Mission (Kailua, Hawaii) and the Native Free Schools, Bombay, India, 1826, 1827 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Copy of a letter to the editor of the Quarterly Review by William Ellis in defense of the Sandwich Island Mission, 1827 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Draft of article supporting William Ellis' position, written by Jeremiah Evarts ( for the North American Review ), (1827) (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - "American Missionaries at the Sandwich Islands," manuscript of articles intended for the Missionary Herald, Circa 1827 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Copy of a letter from Lewis Tappan to an unidentified clergyman presenting Tappan's religious views (intended for publication in the Missionary Herald ?), 1827 November 22 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Incomplete draft of a letter from Jeremiah Evarts to the missionaries in Ceylon, 1828 December 15 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Copies of letters by M. Winslow on Ceylon, intended for publication in the Missionary Herald, 1828 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Missionary Herald, Jeremiah Evarts, editor, 1827 Apr, 1828 Sep, October (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Notes for report, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Fragment of an address to missionaries departing for the Sandwich Islands; excerpts from a letter from (Hiram) Bingham; article on a religious revival in Ohio (all intended for publication), undated (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - The Missionary Herald, 1833 Aug, October (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Twenty-fourth Annual Report of the A. B. C. F. M., 1833 September (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - The Missionary Herald, 1839 Sep, 1840 Dec, 1842 May, 1844 March-1844 May, November (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Sabbath mails
    - Circulars re: memorials to Congress on the subject of Sunday postal service, issued by committees in Boston and New York City, 1828 December 11, 1829 September 29 (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Pamphlets: "An Account of memorials presented to Congress during the last session, by numerous friends of their country and its institutions, praying that the mails may not be transported, nor post offices kept open, on the Sabbath.", 1829 May (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - "Speech of Mr. Frelinghuysen, on his resolution concerning Sabbath mails, in the Senate of the United States, May 8, 1830." (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - List of the members of the House of Representatives, twenty-first Congress, first session, 1829-1830 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Pamphlets, Letter to Eleazer Lord, Esq. in defense of measures for promoting the observance of the Christian Sabbath, by Lewis Tappan, and The Sabbath Manual, by Justin Edwards, 1831 July 20, undated (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - William Penn essays
    - "Original Draft of an Argument in behalf of Indian Rights, written at Washington, March 1829, with a design to be presented to the Government by the Prudential Committee. This afterwards became the groundwork of William Penn ." (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - Letter to the editors of the National Intelligencer from "William Penn" (Jeremiah Evarts) urging them to print nos. I and II of essays on the condition of the American Indians, 1829 July 25 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    - Essays nos. 1 and II, ms. copy, 1829 July 25 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Essays nos. III and IV, ms. copy, 1829 August 1 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Essays nos. V and VI, ms. copy, 1829 August 8 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Essays nos. VII and VIII, ms. copy, 1829 August 15 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Essays nos. IX and X, ms. copy, 1829 August 22 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Essays nos. XI and XII, ms. copy, 1829 August 29 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Essays nos. XIII and XIV, ms. copy, 1829 September 5 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Essays nos. XV and XVI, ms. copy, 1829 September 12 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Essays nos. XVII and XVIII, ms. copy, 1829 September 19 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Essay no. XIX, ms. copy, 1829 November 7 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Essay no. XX, ms. copy, 1829 November 17 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Essay no. XXI, ms. copy, undated (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Title page and proofs for nos. I and II, pamphlet edition (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Proofs for nos. III - V (VI missing) (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Proofs for nos. VII - IX (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Proofs for nos. X - XIII (XIV, XV missing) (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Proofs for nos. XVI - XVIII (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Memorandum entitled "Topics in the Memorial," relating to the memorial to Congress on behalf of the Cherokees, 1830 January 21 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Tabulation of votes in the House of Representatives (by state) on the Indian Rights bill, 1830 May 26 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - "Present state of the Indian Question. To the editors of the National Intelligencer ," ms. copy marked "sent to Mr. Post, Nov. 17, for Messrs. Gales and Seaton." Also ms. copy (not in the hand of Jeremiah Evarts) of a shortened version with the same title, also signed "William Penn", (1830) (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Untitled essay on the state of churches, undated (Box 5, Folder 189A)
  - Personal, Legal, and Financial Papers
    - "A Dissertation on Amor Patriae," student essay, 1800 August 6 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - "Are the abilities of females inferior to those of males?," student essay, 1801 January 5 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Journal, 1801 September 27-1802 January 2 1803 May 22-1803 September 12 1824 January 1-May 29 (Box 5, Folder 192-194)
    - Notebook of compositions, 1801-1802 (Box 5, Folder 194A)
    - Commonplace book and notebook, [1801-1802?] (Box 5, Folder 194A)
    - Notebooks: notes on debates conducted by the Class of 1802 at Yale College, notes on various texts, 1801, 1806, undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Notes and memoranda, miscellaneous, 1801, 1831, undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Meteorological diary (fragments), 1802-1803, (1831) (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - "Keepsakes" - memoranda and prayers in the hand of Samuel Worcester, D. Brown, and A. Bingham, 1819, 1823 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Articles of faith and covenant of Park Street Church, Boston, with a list of members (to 1831 Sep), two editions, 1820, 1825 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Circulars and bulletins (Massachusetts, New York, Connecticut), 1824-1828 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Calling cards, bookplates, undated (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Sermon on the death of Jeremiah Evarts, by Leonard Woods (Box 5, Folder 201)
      See: box 16, folder 447
    - Certificates of membership in Connecticut, Massachusetts and Vermont bar associations, certification as justice of the peace in Middlesex County, Massachusetts, 1806, 1810, 1812 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Agreements between Ethan Smith and Samuel T. Armstrong, and copyright of Ethan Smith to A Dissertation on the Prophecies …, 1810 December 19, 1811 February 19 (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Power of attorney to Jeremiah Evarts granted by Jonas Abrahams, 1823, 1824 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Certificate of release from quarantine on Staten Island, 1824 June 26 (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Records of receipts and expenditures, 1805-1825 (Box 6, Folder 206-208)
    - Property estimates (before move to Charleston), 1804 October 20-1810 May 31 (Box 6, Folder 209)